yankeecandle.com 2017-06-23

# Privacy & Security | Yankee Candle

By continuing to use our site you agree to us using cookies in accordance with our [COOKIE POLICY](http://www.yankeecandle.co.uk/pages-uk-en/customer-service/privacy-cookie-policy) ACCEPT & CLOSE

Logout 

### ???domainchange.title???

???domainchange.confirmation???  

???domainchange.line2??? 

* * *

  * **Shop By Fragrance**
  * **Shop by Color** 
  * **Large Candles** 
  * **New Arrivals** 
  *  **Personalized Photo Candles** 
  * **Get the Look** 

You can track your order by providing your order number.

**Please Note:** You can check the status of orders placed within the last 30 days. Any tracking information will not be provided until after midnight ET of the day your package ships.

**Be the first to know!** Sign up to receive exclusive news and special offers on ways to create a warm and welcoming home.

X

Please enter a valid email address 

Your browser preferences are set to disable/block session cookies.  
In order to proceed, session cookies must be enabled.  
If you need guidance on enabling cookies, please refer to your browser's Help menu.

  * Home
  * Customer Service
  * Privacy & Security

Thank you for visiting www.yankeecandle.com (this " **Web site** "). The Yankee Candle Company, Inc. ( **"Yankee Candle"** or " **we** ") is committed to honoring and protecting your privacy while at the same time providing you with a first rate on-line and shopping experience. As an important part of respecting your privacy, we believe that you have the right to know what information is collected by this Web site, how such information may be used, and what security measures are taken to protect your information. By submitting information through our Web site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not cover any website other than the Web site.

* * *

###  1\. Effective Date of this Privacy Policy

This policy is effective as of 4/24/14.

Return to Customer Service Home

* * *

###  2\. Collection and Use of Information

When you visit our Web site, place an order, request a catalog, otherwise interact with our Web site, and/or contact us via e-mail, certain information is or may be collected. Among the types of information that may be collected are the following:

  * If you create an account, we may collect your name, company, address, phone number, and email address
  * If you place an order, we may collect your name, company, address, phone number, email address, billing information, the kind of product purchased and other information about your purchase
  * If you sign up for emails, we will collect your email address
  * If you request a catalog, we may collect your name, address, and email address
  * If you send us an email, we will collect your name, email address, and any information that you may choose to submit with the e-mail message
  * If you participate in any surveys, contests, wish lists, fundraising, and other voluntary offerings provided on the Web site, we will collect any information you submit as part of such offerings
  * We may collect information about your use of coupons and other discounts on our online store, including the number of discounts used, interests and shopping preferences.
  * We may collect any other information you provide us in response to suggestion forms or other questionnaires.
  * We also collect the following information via technology ( **"Navigational Information"** ). We collect your browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (IP) address, domain name, and/or a date/time stamp for your visit. We also use cookies and URL information to gather information regarding the date and time of your visit and the information for which you searched and which you viewed. We also track the number of visits to a particular page and user-specific information on which pages a guest visits, average length of time spent on the site and similar site usage data. We may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them). **"Cookies"** are small bits of data that a web site can send to your browser and may then be stored on your hard drive. We use cookies in connection with certain features on our Web site. We use the Cookies to enable us to store items in your shopping cart and may also use them to help provide you with customized or tailored information or services. You can set your web browser so that you will always be notified when you receive a Cookie. Persistent Cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions.
  * When you visit this Web site or view one of our e-mails, we may use pixel tags (also called "clear" gifs), tracking links and/or similar technology to note some of the pages you visit on our Web site and personalize your experience. We may also use pixel tags to determine what types of e-mail your browser supports. We may also collect Navigational Information through the use of cookies on the web sites of those companies that serve our advertisements. We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for these outside web sites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of our Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside web sites. In addition, please be aware that these outside web site have their own privacy policies that are applicable to the information they collect.

**Third Party Advertisements**  
We may also use third parties to serve ads on our Web site. We may authorize certain third parties to automatically collect information about your visits to this and other websites, your IP address, your ISP, the browser you use to visit our Web site, the kind of product you purchased (but not your name, address, email address, or telephone number). They do this using cookies, clear gifs, or other technologies. Information collected may be used, among other things, to deliver advertising targeted to your interests and to better understand the usage and visitation of our Site and the other sites tracked by these third parties. This policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies or clear gifs in third party ads, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology. This provision is inapplicable or unenforceable in the State of New Jersey. If wish to opt out of the use your information by third party advertisers visit the NAI website at:[www.networkadvertising.org.] If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>

**Use of Information**  
We use information we collect for the following purposes. We use information to analyze, manage and improve our Web site so that we may continually strive to provide you with the best shopping experience that we possibly can. Information on traffic patterns and the number of page visits and the like helps us to further develop and improve our Web site layout to better meet your needs. Of course, we also use information such as your name, address, phone number, e-mail address and credit card information to contact you, create your account, respond to your inquiries, send you a catalog and to process, deliver and receive payment for your purchases, and provided you the service that you requested (e.g., enter you into a sweepstakes). We may use such information to send you a promotional materials (e.g., a catalog or notify you of services, special offers, new products and other services that we believe may be of interest to you), or to send you administrative emails (e.g., notify you of important new changes in our Web site). We use collected information to help us diagnose problems with our server or other technical issues relating to the performance of the Web site. We may also use this information to improve our products and services and for internal business purposes, such as generating statistics and developing marketing plans.

Return to Customer Service Home

* * *

###  3\. Security

Yankee Candle takes reasonable precautions to protect the security of your personal information. Our Web site is hosted on servers that utilize SSL server software. Any credit card information that you provide is encrypted while it is being transmitted over the Internet in order to reduce the possibility that such information can be read by an unauthorized person. Any credit card information collected by us is stored in files held behind a firewall designed to protect your information and to deny unauthorized access by outside users. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure.

Return to Customer Service Home

* * *

###  4\. Opt In/Opt Out

If you do not wish to receive promotional e-mails (e.g., emails regarding special offers or catalogs) from us, please let us know by sending us an e-mail to info@yankeecandle.com. Please be sure that your e-mail includes your name and address. You may also change your preferences at any time by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of each e-mail you receive from us. When you create and account or complete a feedback form or one of our surveys, you may opt-out of receiving promotional correspondence from us. If you are requesting to be removed from our postal mailing list, please include your name, address and the source code that is located on the back of your catalog. You can also let us know by mailing us c/o The Yankee Candle Company, Inc., Internet and Catalog Sales, P.O. Box 110, South Deerfield, MA 01373-0110, or by calling us at 1-877-803-6890. As noted below, our mailing lists are sometimes made available to companies whose products and services we believe may be of interest to you. If you want to opt-out of any further sharing of your information with such entities please contact us at:

The Yankee Candle Company, Inc.  
P.O. Box 110,  
South Deerfield, MA 01373-0110  
1-877-803-6890  

Despite your indicated e-mail or mail preferences, we may send you service related communication. For example, we may send you notices of any updates to our Terms of Use or Privacy Policy and when you purchase from us online or through our catalogs, or when you choose to enter a sweepstakes or other promotion, we may need to contact you via phone, email or mail to address questions or issues specific to your order or for other service-related reasons, even if you have opted to not receive promotional communications.

If you wish to opt out of sharing information associated with the activities identified in the Third Party Advertisements section above, as noted above visit the NAI website at: www.networkadvertising.org.

Return to Customer Service Home

* * *

###  Your California Privacy Rights

"California's "Shine the Light" law, Civil Code section 1798.83, requires certain businesses to respond to requests from California customers asking about the businesses' practices related to disclosing personal information to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. Alternatively, such businesses may have in place a policy not to disclose personal information of customers to third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes if the customer has exercised an option to opt-out of such information-sharing. We have such a policy. As discussed above, if you want to opt-out of any further sharing of your information, or to inquire about your opt-out rights under Shine the Light, please contact us at:

The Yankee Candle Company, Inc.  
P.O. Box 110,  
South Deerfield, MA 01373-0110  
1-877-803-6890  

If you would like to correct or update any information that you have previously provided, you may do so via e-mail to [info@yankeecandle.com](mailto:info@yankeecandle.com), or by mail or phone call as set forth above.

Return to Customer Service Home

* * *

###  5\. Providing Information to Third Parties

We do not sell or rent your personally identifiable information to third parties without your consent, except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy. To serve you better, we may combine information you give us online, in our stores or through our catalogs. We may also combine that information with publicly available information and information we receive from or cross-reference with our partners and others. We use that combined information to enhance and personalize your shopping experience with us, to communicate with you about our products and events that may be of interest to you, and for other promotional purposes.

Our mailing lists are sometimes made available to companies whose products and services may be of interest to you.

We may collect, store, accumulate certain, or create (by excluding personal data) non-personally identifiable information concerning your use of this Web site, such as information regarding which of our pages are most popular. We may use for any purpose and share or transfer to anyone such non-personally identifiable information in our discretion.

We may disclose any information, including personally identifiable information, we deem necessary, in our sole discretion, to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, including to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on us, or in connection with detection, prevention or investigation of fraud.

We may disclose information about your browsing behavior and/or purchasing behavior while on our web site, including the products you purchased (but not your name, address, email address, telephone number, or any other personally identifiable information), to third party advertisers.

We may contract with companies or persons to provide certain services including credit card processing, shipping, data management, promotional services, etc. (our "Service Providers") . We provide our Service Providers with the information needed for them to perform these services. Our Service Providers are required not to use your information other than to provide the services requested by us.

Although unlikely, in certain instances we may disclose any information, including your personally identifiable information, when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities who may be causing injury to you, to Yankee Candle or to others (including re: any violation of this Privacy Policy or our Terms of Use) or to otherwise protect or defend the rights or property of you, Yankee Candle or others.

We may share some or all of your personally identifiable information with our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, "Affiliates"), in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell our company, or all or a portion of our business or assets. In such transactions, user information, including personally identifiable information, generally is one of the transferred business assets. By submitting your personal information on the Web site you agree that your data may be transferred to any company that acquires our company, or all or a portion of our business, or our assets, including through bankruptcy proceedings. The acquiring company will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personally identifiable information as described in this Privacy Policy.

Return to Customer Service Home

* * *

###  6\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post the revised policy here. As we may make changes at any time, we suggest that you periodically consult this Privacy Policy. Please note that our rights to use your personally identifiable information will be based on the privacy policy in effect at the time the information is used. If we make any material changes in the way we use your personally identifiable information, we will notify you by sending you an e-mail to the last e-mail address you provided to us and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our Web site. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective upon the earlier of thirty (30) calendar days following our dispatch of an e-mail notice to you or thirty (30) calendar days following our posting of notice of the changes on our Web site. These changes will be effective immediately for new users. If you object to any such revisions you must cease using our Web site. Continued use of our Web site following notice of any such revisions shall indicate your acknowledgement of such revisions and your agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of the revised Privacy Policy.

Return to Customer Service Home

* * *

###  7\. European Union Users

YOU EXPRESSLY CONSENT TO YANKEE CANDLE'S (OR ITS AFFILIATES) PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY. YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE PROCESSED BY YANKEE CANDLE (OR ITS AFFILIATES) IN THE COUNTRY WHERE IT WAS COLLECTED AND IN THE UNITED STATES. UNITED STATES LAWS REGARDING PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE LESS STRINGENT THAN THE LAWS IN YOUR COUNTRY.

IF YOU REPRESENT AN ORGANIZATION, YOU WILL BE RESPONSIBLE TO ENSURE THAT EACH MEMBER OF YOUR ORGANIZATION (INCLUDING EMPLOYEES AND CONTRACTORS) ABOUT WHOM PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE PROVIDED TO YANKEE CANDLE (OR ITS AFFILIATES) HAS GIVEN HIS OR HER EXPRESS CONSENT TO YANKEE CANDLE'S (AND ITS AFFILIATES) PROCESSING OF SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION.

Return to Customer Service Home

* * *

###  8\. A Note About Children

We do not intentionally gather personally identifiable information from visitors who are under the age of 13.

Return to Customer Service Home

Copyright 2017 The Yankee Candle Company, Inc. All Rights Reserved [ ](https://www.bizrate.com/ratings_guide/merchant_detail__mid--138631.html?rf=sur "See Yankee Candle Company Review at Bizrate.com") [](http://secure.trust-guard.com/security/8227) [SSL Certificate](https://www.digicert.com/ssl-certificate.htm)
